Let's discuss about binders.
Binder is the IPC in their process communication mechanism in Android.
As you can see from this architecture diagram, binder is the bridge between applications or application
framework and the system service.
Why do we need binders?
Android apps and system services run in a separate process for security, stability and memory management.
But they need to share the data.
That's why we need binders any app in order to communicate with assistant system service or HAL has
to go through a binder.
So in short, Binder allows two different processes to communicate with each other.
These are the major features of Binder IPC, a kernel driver, to facilitate internal process communication.
So basically Binder is a kernel driver which is implemented in Linux to facilitate inter process communication.
It's a lightweight RBC.
It's a lightweight, remote procedure communication.
Its purpose a straight pole for processing request.
It allows synchronous communication between the processors.